<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Answers for Æneas Mcleod town clerk of Edinburgh, to the petition presented by some particular persons, in name of the Council and Community of the said burgh, to his Grace His Majesties High Commissioner and the right honourable the Estates of Parliament.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B01409</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3462B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R172384</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52211672</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52211672</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175405</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B01409)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175405)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2732:23)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Answers for Æneas Mcleod town clerk of Edinburgh, to the petition presented by some particular persons, in name of the Council and Community of the said burgh, to his Grace His Majesties High Commissioner and the right honourable the Estates of Parliament.</title>
                  <author>Mcleod, Æneas, fl. 1695.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n. ,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Date and place of publication suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Mcleod, Æneas, fl. 1695 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Edinburgh (Scotland). --  Town Council --  Trials, litigation, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Town clerks --  Scotland --  Edinburgh --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Edinburgh (Scotland) --  Officials and employees --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>Kayla Ondracek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>Kayla Ondracek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="answers">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:175405:1"/>
            <head>ANSWERS For <hi>Aeneas Mcleod</hi> Town Clerk of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> to the Petition preſented by ſome particular perſons, in name of the Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh, to his Grace His Majeſties High Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioner and the right honourable the Eſtates of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament.</head>
            <p>THe ſaid <hi>Aeneas</hi> having Legally Acquired a Gift for Life of his Office, from the Magiſtrats and Town Council of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> (to whom that Power does unqueſtionably belong) upon payment of <hi>19000 Merks:</hi> And having been in Poſſeſſion by vertue of his Right, for more than ſeven years, whereby he hath the benefit of a Poſſeſſory Judgment: And having ever ſince his Admiſſion, been moſt faithful to his Truſt, and more exact than his Prede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors in Office, and keeped the Registers as well in order, as any other in the Kingdom: It is confidently relyed on, that his Grace and the honourable Estates, will not ſustain Proceſs against him before the Parliament. Becauſe</p>
            <p n="1">
               <hi>1.</hi> That he is not obliged to anſwer upon a ſummar Complaint, in a matter of ſo great Conſequence, being in effect, the annulling of his Right for Life, which according to the Acts of Regulation <hi>1672,</hi> can onely be by a Reduction, wherein Terms will be granted to produce, and the Reaſons debate <hi>in praeſentia</hi> of the Lords of Seſſion: Eſpecially, ſeing he hath a Poſſeſſory Judgment, which gives him this Priviledge of time to prepare himſelf, for defending his Gift as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p n="2">
               <hi>2.</hi> The Complaint being preſented by the Town Council of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> there ought no Proceſs to be ſuſtained thereupon, unleſs there had been an antecedent Act of the ſaid Town Council and Community warranting the ſame; By the want of which, it appears that this Purſuit is onely raiſed by particular perſons upon privat deſigns to ſurpriſe the ſaid <hi>Aeneas</hi> and overturn his Right, when the Parliament cannot allow a full Hearing, being otherways taken up with the great Concerns of the Nation. Eſpecially</p>
            <p n="3">
               <hi>3.</hi> The Ground of the Complaint, being ſeveral matters of Fact, Inſpection of Registers, and Examination of the Warrants thereof; which can onely be cleared by Cognition of the <hi>Forms</hi> and <hi>Practicks</hi> relative to the ſaid Office: It cannot be ſuppoſed, that the High Court of Parliament, can ſpare ſo much time as is neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary, for ſo tedious a Cognition as will be requiſite, before this Affair can be De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termined. Hence</p>
            <p n="4">
               <hi>4</hi> The wiſdom of the Nation hath determined by repeated Acts of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, that all Civil Actions ſhall be firſt brought before, and decided by the Judge Ordinary, <hi>particularly</hi> Act <hi>45.</hi> Parl. <hi>2d.</hi> Ja. <hi>1. In theſe words, anent Bills
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:175405:2"/>of Complaint, whilks may not be determined in Parliament, for divers Cauſes belonging to the common profit of the Realm: it is Ordained, that the ſaids Bills be execute, and determined by the Judges<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and Officers of the Courts, whom to they pertain of Law,</hi> &amp;c. Where the Parliament Declares, that the common profit of the Realm, will not permit their medling in Civil Actions, in the first Inſtance: <hi>As alſo by</hi> Act. <hi>26.</hi> Parl. <hi>5.</hi> Ja. <hi>3. It is Statute, that the Partie Complaining, in any part of the Realm, ſhall firſt come to his Judge Ordinary,</hi> &amp;c. As it cannot be denyed, but this is a Civil Cauſe, and either can be Remeided by Law, in which caſe the ordinary Judicatories are Patent: or the Clerks Right can not be overturned by the Laws and Cuſtoms of this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, as being his Legal Propertie and Free-hold; in which caſe, it is certain the Parliament will not deprive him thereof, in their J<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>DICATIVE Capacity.</p>
            <p n="5">
               <hi>5.</hi> The Remead by Parliament is extraordinary, when the Supream ordinary Judge hath committed Iniquity, ſo that there remains no other means of Redreſs: <hi>ſed non recurrendum eſt ad Remedium extraordinarium quamdiu locus eſt ordinario,</hi> Eſpecially ſeing the Kings Leidges can run no Hazard of being Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged, ſince there is always recourſe to the Parliament by Proteſtation for Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mead of Law which is now cleared: whereas the bringing in Actions in the firſt inſtance to that High Court would obſtruct publick buſineſs, and be a greater expence upon the Nation then the value of any ſuch Actions.</p>
            <p n="6">
               <hi>6.</hi> The Clerk will not trouble his Grace, and the right Honourable, the Eſtates, with an particular anſwer to the pretended Malverſations lybelled; ſince, as he is confident, the Parliament will remit the ſame to the Judge ordinary: ſo he will make it appear before the ſaid Judge, that he hath behaved in all points of the ſaid Office, as a moſt faithful, Exact, and dutyful Clerk, and that even in all the particulars Lybelled on.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Laſtly,</hi> The Town has no reaſon to complain anent the Act of Council, <hi>1678.</hi> Seing it is in their power, to Reſcind the ſame in all time coming, without pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice to the ſaid <hi>Aeneas,</hi> to whom it is already <hi>jus queſitum,</hi> and cannot be changed to his Prejudice, without a manifest Violation of privat Rights, and the known and eſtabliſhed Rules of Law, whereby all Rights are Regulat, by the Laws standing the time of the acquiring the Right, and no Laws are drawn back to Regulate the paſt: and as this is a known Rule in the Law univerſallie received; ſo it is more eſpecially our Laws, as appears by the <hi>Act 19.</hi> Par. <hi>10 Ja. 6.</hi> And ſeing the ſaid <hi>Aeneas,</hi> did upon the faith of that Act, and Gift founded upon it, purchaſe his Imployment at a dear Rate; as alſo, that the Act in it ſelf contains nothing but what is Juſt, and was enacted upon occaſions equally hurtful to the Town and their Clerks, as is well known, to ſuch as know any thing of the Affairs of the Town of <hi>Edinburgh:</hi> and that the Gift contains nothing ſingular, but what can be Juſtified by abundance of inſtances, when the matter comes to be Diſcuſſed be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Judge Ordinary. Therefore the deſire of the Petitioner ought to be refuſed, and the whole matter remitted to the Judge Ordinary, as accords, eſpecially ſeing the ſaid <hi>Aeneas</hi> has raiſed a Summons of Declarator, anterior to the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
